Boheng Lin

https://bohenglin.github.io

Boheng0507@gmail.com

(781) 827-9608

SUMMARY

I am a highly adaptable fresh graduate with a diverse background. With task prioritization and time management skills, I completed the usual 4-year bachelor's in 2 years' time while excelling in academics, part time jobs, internships and a student organization. In the final semester for my master's degree, I also adapted to different roles with ease as I worked for two internships while completing the degree.

SKILLS

- Databases: Access, PostgreSQL & Azure data factory, DataBricks, data engineering
- Programming Languages: SAS, Python, R, HTML

Visualization: <u>Tableau</u> & PowerBI

- Analytics: Unsupervised (clustering) and supervised (regression) machine learning. Statistics, Web scraping, GIS, background in economics and finance.
- Communication: Bilingual in Chinese Mandarin and English, event planning and execution.

EDUCATION

Tufts University

M.S. Data Analytics Recipient of Data Analytics Scholarship 2019, GPA: 3.7/4.0; December 2020

University of Massachusetts Amherst, USA

B.S. Resource Economics (Graduated with Cum Laude Honor)

August 2019

- Recipient of Chancellor's Scholarship 2017 and Faculty Award for Academic Excellence Scholarship 2019; Cumulative GPA 3.85/4.0, Dean's List every term, outstanding Academic Achievement by the Honour
- Society of Phi Kappa Phi 2018;

Anglo Chinese Junior College, Singapore

Singapore-Cambridge GCE A Level Certificate

December 2016

- Graduated in top 10% of the class, with 5 distinctions in Singapore-Cambridge GCE A Level 2016;
- Scholastic Merit Award.

PROJECTS (Link to all projects)

Image Compression using Singular Value Decomposition (Matlab)

Used singular value decomposition to assess the effects of compressing an image of 1528*1225 pixels using the top 10, 25, 50 and 100 largest singular values and explore the possible optimum number of singular values to be used for the compression.

Exploring the inconsistency of KMeans in identifying breast cancer cells using principal components (Python)

- Used principal component analysis and dimension reduction to facilitate KMeans algorithm to assess the consistency and accuracy of classifying malignant and benign breast cancer cells;
- Compared classified label to the original label and determined low applicability of using KMeans on PC dimension reduced dataset.

Exploring the Representativeness of Batting Average on Major League Baseball Players' Performances (Python)

- Used pandas, re, requests, and bs4 (BeautifulSoup) to perform web scraping, extracting MLB players' scores with about 350 entries;
- Used sklearn and pandas to perform ridge regressions, linear regressions, supervised machine learning and principal components analysis to assess the representativeness of the batting average score

CT Level Analysis on Gun Violence And the Demographics in Boston, Massachusetts (R Language)

- Used dplyr, clusteval, rgdal to perform supervised learning, K-Means clustering and linear regression on data set with 1400 entries;
- Conducted quantitative and qualitative analysis on gun violence and the demographics in Boston from 2010 through 2018 link

EXPERIENCE

Retail Business Services LLC, a company of Ahold Delhaize USA Business Intelligence & Analytics Co-op

June 2020 – Dec 2020

- Responsible for technical design and development of business intelligence solutions, constructed copy data pipeline independently in Azure data factory;
- Using pyspark, sparklyr, SparkR and SQL to construct analysis codes on Databricks for a customer segmentation project;
- Assisted in constructing scripts that enables auto detection of metadata for files and folders at a given path.

China Blue Sustainability Institute

April 2020 - Present

Project Assistant Intern

- Explored and assisted in developing database for iFISH project, including fishing related data collection, data analysis and methodology development;
- Analysed and construct visualizations based on collected data and constructed analysis reports published on company's public WeChat account.

Carmichael Dining Center, Tufts University, Medford

September 2019 – May 2020

Student Manager

- Assisted in various dining units in providing quality services, able to multitask under stress and fast pace working environment;
- Supervised and effectively communicated with all student workers complete assigned tasks timely;
- Bridged between the management team and student workers to achieve operational and customer service objectives.

Shenzhen SME Credit Financing Guarantee Group Co. Ltd Shenzhen, China

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Assistant to Manager Intern

- Compiled and analysed the Group's internal data including guarantee amounts, mortgages and projects completion statues, and reported relevant findings to respective managers;
- Processed projects data including data gathering, data cleaning and cross validation for '2019 SME

Independently reviewed and analysed SMEs' balance sheets and profit and loss statements;

Collaborated with legal department and finance department of the Group on several projects and new mortgages.

Isenberg School of Management

September 2018 – December 2018

Massachusetts Small Business Development Center, Springfield

Business Consultant Intern

Conducted market research and reviewed business plans for clients;

- Prepared and analysed financial projects for clients including profit and loss and balance sheets;
- Met with clients to advise them on both marketing strategies and financial cash flows.

University of Massachusetts Amherst Dinning Hall, Amherst Student Worker

September 2017 – May 2019

Prepared ingredients, made sushi and deli sandwiches and served food, able to complete given tasks independently.

Din Tai Fung (Tampines Mall), Singapore

June 2015 – February 2016

Provided quality service under fast pace environment, able to multi-task under pressure.

Buddhist Compassion Relief Tzu Chi Foundation, Singapore Member Volunteer

March 2014 – May 2016

Actively engaged in monthly community recycling and campaigning, carried out activities at a care home.

Berries World School of Learning (TPCL) Pte Ltd, Singapore

March 2014 – December 2015

Teaching Assistant

Assisted six teachers in the conduction of lessons from primary one to three, smoothly worked with teachers with different teaching styles.

ACTIVITIES

University of Massachusetts Amherst

The Honour Society of Phi Kappa Phi member

March 2019 – March 2020

International Student Ambassador

December 2017 – December 2018

Coordinated information sharing and outreach for potential applicants from Singapore and China.

Chinese Music Association

September 2017 – May 2019

- Treasure and Signature Responsibility Officer, responsible for applying, budgeting, and managing group's funds of about 2000 US dollars
- Proposed and organized fundraising that financed in total of about 1000 US dollars for the group.

Anglo Chinese Junior College

Competitive Swimming Team January 2015 – December 2016

Boys' Team Captain, finalist in the 57th National Schools Swimming Championship (Singapore)